英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with Day 2 for the month of September.
Hi everyone, I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
今回のテーマは、Colors 色です。
では、ウォーミングアップとしてこの3つを英語で言ってみよう。
赤、青、黄色、英語でどうぞ。
答えは、
Red, blue, yellow.
Okay, that was easy.
では、紺色、水色は英語でどのように表現しますか?
とてもシンプルに表現できます。
一緒に練習して言えるようになりましょう。
では、一回目の挑戦です。
Okay, it's time for your first try.
F.P.R. Training
では、僕の言う日本語を時間内に英語で表現してください。
一つ目、まずこの色を表現しましょう。
明るい青。
答えは、ブライト・ブルー。
では、ブライト・ブルーを使ってこの文を言ってみよう。
このネクタイは明るい青です。
次の色を確認しましょう 紺色 英語でどうぞ
答えはダークブルー もしかしてネイビーを言ったかもしれませんが
ネイビーと聞くと多くの人は海軍を思い浮かべるかもしれません
より伝わりやすいのはダークブルー
ではダークブルーを使ってこちらを言ってみよう
紺色のネクタイを探しています
I'm looking for, 彼に言いましょう。
どうぞ。
続いての色は、水色。
How do you say 水色 in English?
The answer is, light blue.
もちろん、ブルーのトーンはいろいろあるんですけれども、
分かりやすいのは、light blue。
それを使って、こちら。
Is there a light blue color on this shirt?
The next color is light gray.
How do you say that in English?
That's right. Light gray.
Let's use that to say these two sentences over time.
The uncle is over there.
薄いグレーのスーツを着ています。
My uncle is...
から言いましょう。
どうぞ。
続いての色は、
濃いグレー。
英語でどうぞ。
そうです。
Dark gray。
それを使って、
こちらを言ってみよう。
このお店には、
そのシャツは、濃いグレーしかありません。
続いての色は、薄い緑。
薄緑っていうのは、
ライトグリーン。
では、この2文を言ってみよう。
うちの制服は、薄い緑です。
当社の企業カラーです さあ続いてこの2分を行ってみよう
私のジャケット探しています濃い緑です
母が私にこの明るい緑のシャツをくれました
では続いて紅葉についての文です
紅葉はすごく色鮮やかです
The autumn leavesを使ってどうぞ
OK, how was your first round? Did you try to say each one?
では、ここで回答例をチェックしましょう。
OK, now you can check your answers with mine. Listen closely.
このネクタイは明るい青です。
This tie is bright blue.
紺色のネクタイを探しています。
I'm looking for a dark blue tie.
このシャツの水色はありますか?
Do you have this shirt in light blue?
おじはあそこにいます。薄いグレーのスーツを着ています。
My uncle is over there. He's wearing a light gray suit.
このお店にはそのシャツは濃いグレーしかありません。
This shop only has that shirt in dark gray.
うちの制服は薄い緑です。当社の企業カラーです。
Our uniforms are light green. It's our company color.
私のジャケット探しています。濃い緑です。
I'm looking for my jacket. It's dark green.
母が私にこの明るい緑のシャツをくれました。
My mom gave me this bright green shirt.
紅葉はすごく色鮮やかです。
The autumn leaves are so colorful.
紅葉のことはわかりやすく言うと、
The autumn leaves.
Autumnの代わりにfallもよく使います。
The fall leavesも正解。
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
それではみなさん、今学習した表現をテンポよくもう一度言ってみましょう。
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two. Here we go!
このネクタイは明るい青です。
This tie is bright blue.
紺色のネクタイを探しています。
I'm looking for a dark blue tie.
このシャツの水色はありますか?
Do you have this shirt in light blue?
おじはあそこにいます。
薄いグレーのスーツを着ています。
My uncle is over there. He's wearing a light gray suit.
このお店には、そのシャツは濃いグレーしかありません。
This shop only has that shirt in dark gray.
うちの制服は薄い緑です。当社の企業カラーです。
Our uniforms are light green. It's our company color.
私のジャケットを探しています。濃い緑です。
I'm looking for my jacket. It's dark green.
母が私にこの明るい緑のシャツをくれました。
My mom gave me this bright green shirt.
Kouyou wa sugoku iro azayaka desu.
The autumn leaves are so colorful.
Okay, time's up.
Well, how was your second try?
Great job today.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.